<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" source="1904-02-26.xml">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="s">The Genuine Jew - 1904-02-26</title>
            <title level="a">1904-02-26</title>
            <author>Multiple Authors</author>
            <editor>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </editor>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>TGJ</edition>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Translation</resp>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </respStmt>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </publisher>
            <pubPlace>Vienna</pubPlace>
            <date when="2025">2025</date>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">
                  <p>You are free to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format; adapt — remix, transform, and build upon the material
                     for any purpose, even commercially.</p>
                  <p>The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms. Under the following terms:</p>
                  <p>Attribution — You must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use. No additional restrictions — You may not apply legal terms or technological measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license permits.</p>
                  <p>Notices:</p>
                  <p>You do not have to comply with the license for elements of the material in the public domain or where your use is permitted by an applicable exception or limitation. No warranties are given. The license may not give you all of the permissions necessary for your intended use. For example, other rights such as publicity, privacy, or moral rights may limit how you use the material.</p>
               </licence>
               <p>Copyright 2021 Österreichische Nationalbibliothek</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>A</country>
                  <settlement>Vienna</settlement>
                  <repository>Austrian National Library</repository>
                  <collection></collection>
                  <idno>429702-D NEU PER</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when-iso="1904-02-19">1904-02-26</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Sonngasse 27, Lemberg</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
   <facsimile source="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/anno?aid=emj&amp;datum=19040226">
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="1">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|1|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="2">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|2|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="3">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|3|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="4">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|4|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="5">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|5|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="6">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|6|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="7">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|7|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="8">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|8|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div type="heading" n="1" style="one column">
            
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">1.Jahrgang 	Nr. 4 </foreign>	1st year</p>
         </div>
         <div type="title" n="1">
            <head>
               <hi rend="bold">The Geniune Jew</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Organ for yiddish matters</p>
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">DER WAHRE JUDE</foreign></p>
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">Organ für die Gesammtinteressen des Judenthums</foreign></p>
         </div>
         <div type="editorial" n="1" style="two columns">
            <cb n="1"/>
            <table rows="4" cols="2">
               <head>The Geniune Jew costs</head>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">In <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs></cell>
                  <cell role="data">Abroad</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 8 Kronen</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 12 Francs</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 4 "</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 6 "</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 2.50 "</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 3.50 "</cell>
               </row>
            </table>
            <p><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>,<date when-iso="1904-02-19"> Friday 26th 1904</date></p>
            <cb n="2"/>
            <p>
               <lb/>Adverts are cheaply calculated
               <lb/>All letters and money send to:
               <lb/><foreign xml:lang="de">Redaction "Der wahre Jude",<rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place003">Sonnengasse 27</ref></rs></foreign>
               <lb/>The Genuine Jew is published every Friday.
               <lb/><foreign xml:lang="de"><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lemberg</ref></rs>, <date when-iso="1904-02-26">den 26. Februar 1904</date></foreign>.</p>
         </div>
         <lb/>
         <div type="article" style="two columns" n="1">
           <head><hi rend="bold">The Genuine Jew
            <lb/>Twice a week</hi></head>
            <p>We are delighted to announce to our readers and our friends that our hope with “The Genuine Jew”, to create a readership and be of use for our brothers, especially our pious brothers, was fulfilled. Already, after 
               three issues of “The Genuine Jew”, our paper has gained popularity among the people. Starting on Thursday, people start to ask every tobacconist's, every bookstore and even the editor’s office, whether the new edition 
               has already arrived. Our readers can barely wait until the print has finished. Everything is bought, for example, we have not a single copy left of No. 3, although we printed a huge batch.</p>
            <p>Not only the news about the war made people interested in this paper. From all over, people tell us that the audience, especially our Orthodox brothers who are the reason we established the paper, are very satisfied. 
               The articles mainly focusing on Jewish topics proved popular among the general public. For the first time, there is a Jewish newspaper in <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs> which every pious Jew 
               can read, including his wife and children without having to fear to stray from the path of righteousness.</p>
            <p>The audience is content with us and we are content with the audience. This mutual satisfaction allows us to improve and prosper our paper.</p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[1]</p>
            <p>Voices from different quarters ask for the paper to be released <hi rend="italic">daily</hi>, but we want to follow what our scholars of blessed memories have said: “If you grasp too much, you will grasp nothing” 
               and not to put too much work on our backs. Therefore, we decided to first  carry out a small test, namely: from next week on </p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">The Genuine Jew
               <lb/>comes out twice a week
               <lb/>Tuesday and Friday
            </p>
            <p>Friday will stay like it is now with the same content. On Tuesday, we will preliminarily write about news from the war front, politics and similar topics our readers care about and cannot wait for until Friday.</p>
            <p>We live in serious times. More wars will follow the war between <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place19">Japan</ref></rs>. The whole world, generally the Jew, 
               is curious to know what happens around the globe. And if there is no Jewish press he has to purchase newspapers in other languages which are more expensive and he might not understand them well. 
               Therefore, if “The Genuine Jew” comes out twice a week, he will be able to  satisfy his needs concerning a <hi rend="italic">Jewish</hi> paper.</p>
            <p style="text-align:center">The price of our paper “The Genuine Jew”
               <lb/>twice a week will be
            </p>
            <table rows="3" cols="1" style="text-align:center">
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 12 Francs</cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 6 "</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 3.50 "</cell>
               </row>
            </table>
            <p style="text-align:center">Single Issues: Friday 10 heller, Tuesday 6 heller.</p>
            <p style="text-align:right">The editorial office.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" style="one column" n="2">
            <head rend="bold" style="text-align:center">The cultus elections in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs></head>
            <p>In the first articles of three issues of “The Genuine Jew” various writers rightfully pointed at several important questions regarding Jewish existence which are not handled as they should be. The writers allude 
               to our ample negligence of Jewry as in every nook we are pointing to in order to criticize. The upbringing of our children, our religious education, our rabbis; briefly speaking: at home, in school and even in the 
               rabbis’ dwellings. Everywhere is room for improvements and every writer asks: Who is at fault?</p>
            <p>Who is at fault? Answering this question is not easy because we are all guilty: our sons and our elders, young and old, we all are guilty that <cb/>the Jewry is getting weaker and weaker. Our parents do not parent 
               our children well. Our religion teachers teach badly. Even our rabbis do not have any power, any influence. It has to become better here. Because of the rabbinical question, are our rabbis without power or influence, 
               they are dependent on our cultus board and therefore do not dare to open their mouth and demand for things to improve.</p>
            <p>And here we come to our main conclusion to our question: Who is at fault? Guilty is our cultus board, the leaders of our communities.  They are not taking a stance and act correctly according to their duty.</p>
            <p>The communities act as  autonomous bodies. This means they have the right to manage all affairs regarding their community on their own</p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">[2]</p><pb/>
            <p>without anyone intervening. In any other nation an autonomous entity like this would act in favour of its own people. It would use its force and influence to improve the prevailing conditions. Here however, it is 
               different. Our ministry of cultural affairs mainly consists of mere <hi rend="italic">chanceries</hi>. Books are taken care of, they stipulate how things should be running. There is an accountant, a cashier, and a 
               controller. The council gets together every once in a while to talk about current matters, a bit about politics, about the Landtag elections and things like that. But they do not talk about Jewish matters, about 
               the significant interests of the Jewish people - those are not discussed as if the council is not responsible for them. </p>
            <p>
               The cause of this is very simple. In most Galician cities, the majority of Jews living there are pious ones. However, the electives in the ministry are mainly “progressive” lawyers who are not particularly interested 
               in Jewish matters. Whenever this council gets together in a meeting, they are clueless what to do in favour of religion and faith. First of all, they do not know a lot about it and do not know how to enact a remedy. 
               Secondly, they are more progressive and cannot act against their own opinion of Jewry. It is already sufficient if they do not do anything to harm Jewry as they are afraid of the pious populace. More than that, 
               everything is neglected. The council does not care about the religious education, not about the rabbinical question, not about the תּלמוד־תּורה (Talmetoyre - a tuition-free elementary school maintained by the community 
               for poor children), they do not care about Jewish upbringing. Therefore, everything here is foul and bad. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Why do we talk about this whole thing here? Shortly, there will be an election for the new board of culture in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>, the capital of the country. The smaller towns 
               look up to the big city and adapt themselves towards it. The state of the big city has an influence on the small towns. If everything is working properly in the city, everything will be alright in the smaller cities. 
               Moreover, elections in a big community, a community of major cultural and religious importance - like the one in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs> - are significant for the whole country and 
               have a bigger impact than just locally. The outcome of the elections can influence the entire country -  for the better or for the worse. And we pious Jews need to see that it will be better.</p>
            <p>We do not want to look into the programs and moreover single individuals and parties yet. There still will be enough time for that. Today we want to concern ourselves with the question in order to remind our pious 
               brothers of the upcoming elections which are very important for the Jewry and<pb/> to call on them to pay their overdue taxes in order to not lose their right to vote. They should make an effort to attain as many votes 
               as they can. For these elections, every vote has an immense value. This time they need to use their voice for the benefit of the true Jewry. If we manage to improve the situation in the ministry of culture and education, 
               everything will gradually improve.</p>
               <p style="text-align:right">- The observer.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" style="two columns" n="3">
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Our daughter’s education.
               <lb/>II.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               I must admit that the impression my first article on pious family has made, was bigger than I anticipated. This shows that I portrayed the situation correctly. The critique, what I have criticised was right therefore. 
               However, it is not as easy to point a way to improve the conditions. The main action is for the parents to care more about their daughter’s education as much as they should stick to the rule: “One who is created needs 
               to marry, but does not need to live”. This means: do only men need to live piously? Do only our sons need to be educated well, Jewish, and piously, but not our daughters? Women today play a big role in our family life. 
               Not only is the Jewry at home, the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q191498">kashrut</ref>, the desecration of Sabbath, amongst other things, dependent on them, because the men are busy making a living to 
               take care of the household. They are not responsible for the children’s and particularly the daughter’s upbringing, but if their daughters are not educated Jewish, one can imagine them wanting to raise their daughters 
               again. Still, the pious Jewry should strive to educate their daughters as well as their sons. They have to see that their daughter’s do not leave school which is a legal requirement which no one can withdraw from. 
               They have to see that their daughter’s do not spend their days reading corrupt novels which turn them bad. They have to see that their daughter’s educate themselves economically, they should know cooking, baking, 
               sewing, stitching and so on. It is necessary for every Jewish housewife to concern themselves with this matter if they do not want to deal with  some blockhead, if they do not want to be associated with bad company, 
               and to not be unhappy with themselves and make their parents miserable. If they strive for education and knowledge, they can gather enough Jewish knowledge. They can learn to understand our prayers and our poems, 
               learn a bit of Jewish history, they need to know how much the Jewish people have suffered for their religion and their faith, how many martyrs have devoted themselves, were burnt and drowned for our holy religion. 
               They therefore should be planted deep in the young hearts, love, and respect for their people, their religion, to their customs, and their performances. At that time, the honest, pious Jew has not been the target 
               of mockery, at that time they were not looked at like people from past generations, at that time they felt what every pious Jew felt, back then they would know that they are
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[3]</p><pb/>
            <p>
               Jewish daughters, that they have Jewish duties. At that time, the old, magnificent Jewish family life could develop and it will be as it was written in the scripture: May peace dwell in your community and tranquillity 
               in your homes!
            </p>
            <p>
               But this kind of education will also be beneficial in a relationship. It is well-known how hard it is these days for Jews to make a living. The Jewish daughters, as they are being brought up nowadays, do not want to 
               be involved in any of this. They have to go with the latest fashion. They ruin their parents as girls and the men as women. However, if they are being educated economically and piously, then they will understand how 
               hard it is to earn money, then they will try to help out their parents if they are struggling and if the parents do not need their help, then at least they will not be their burden and ruin anything by being prodigal.
            </p> 
            <p>
               As I said, it is not easy to provide any specific proposal for the education of the Jewish daughters. The main thing is that the parents will start to care more about their daughters, they should strive to teach them 
               Jewish and economically. This then will result in great advantages for the Jewry and the capital of parents and men alike. 
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:right">Ben Solomon.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" style="two columns" n="4">
            <head rend="bold" style="text-align:center">The luxury
               (<lb/>A letter to the editor.)
            </head>
            <p>
               As I saw your new newspaper “The Genuine Jew” for the first time, I was so delighted that I felt like I had taken a holiday. It is quite something, indeed will a “genuine Jew” tell the truth. Unfortunately, these times 
               are filled with lies and the truth hides in the corner, it is afraid to show itself. Therefore, as you are not afraid to tell the truth, I will make time to talk about the passion of your newspaper. I also want to show 
               our dearest audience the truth a little bit, really show our honest Jews who are not ashamed of reading an honest and truthfully written paper and want to draw your attention to the cancer which is sucking the Jew dry. 
               And no one wants to budge from what is causing it: the bitter word:   <hi rend="italic">the luxury</hi>. It is very easily said, one needs to shout it so loudly so that it will be heard at the end of the world 
               (from one corner of the world to the other), however that only makes the Jew unhappy and hated by our Christian neighbours.
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi rend="italic">The luxury</hi>, not only ruins our material situation, but also elicits a type of envy among Christians. They really think that every Jewish person possesses great wealth and where should he have gotten 
               that fortune if not from the Christians themselves. How? Surely not in an honest manner. The Christian also knows that Jews do not earn no fifty percent from any kind of merchandise. No doubt, the Jew is a swindler, a con 
               man which the Christian cannot find out about. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Let’s look at the truth, apart from the big, rich man making around a thousand guilder or only five hundred a piece. No matter how many pieces of clothes he is making, it needs to be made of velvet, a fashionable piece, 
               another vogue one, two or three hats, a golden chain.  Even though a whole crowd has gathered for a marriage, already sitting in carved benches<cb/> ooking at each other in, questioning: have already earned enough for 
               <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q102477">Sabbath</ref>? But all those trifles have to exist. This is as if a law given to <rs type="person"><ref source="person065">Moses</ref></rs> from <rs type="place"><ref source="place158">Sinai</ref></rs>
               - an unchangeable rule. One has to go outside exhausted to look who thinks they know what is going on. How do the Christians expect that the worn out woman for certain has a vast fund of fifty thousand guilds at home. 
               He is oblivious that if only he would pay attention, he would hear how high poverty soars there… but the Jewish maidservants work scattered across the <rs type="place"><ref source="place101">Rhineland</ref></rs>. 
               Are they making serious business with that? They are making a fool out of themselves again and again while poverty keeps growing. And deprives us of our livelihood, this is our misfortune. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Once we manage to look away from what makes hate, will the luxury bring misery from another time. The <hi rend="italic">taxes</hi> are measured based on our clothes and hat. The tax inspector understands that if one 
               earns a lot, one can buy their wife a nice hat and make a beautiful dress. One fact I’d like to highlight which is truly sad, but very true. Not long ago, the tax-inspector went to a bigger city in <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs> 
               with his wife to buy her a hat and went inside a shop. We Jewish people understand that the tax-inspector is a great nobleman. The salesclerk showed them an expensive hat, but they said: they want a very cheap hat. 
               Truly, they bought a hat for a few guilds. Meanwhile a Jewish woman also entered to buy herself a hat. First they showed her cheap hats, but she was not okay with any cheap hats. Finally they showed her a hat for 25 
               guilds. Only this one finally pleased her, she did not negotiate long and soon left with the hat in her possession and went home with her bargain… The tax inspector watched this happen and inquired who that woman was. 
               Once he comes to collect her taxes from the woman with the beautiful hat, he will calculate her taxes based on 50 guilds. The eyes of the shopkeeper darkened once he heard that. He ran up to the tax collector and wanted 
               to yell. He swears by his bones that he is incapable of paying taxes of that amount, he was not helped by the woman buying a hat for some 20 guilds if he has to pay massive taxes as well. This case alone already shows 
               what consequences luxury has for us. In another article I want to make an effort to prove with numbers how far luxury pushes the Jew into poverty and how the situation can be improved without luxury. 
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:right" rend="italic">Shikleh from <rs type="place"><ref source="place159">Tyszmenica</ref></rs></p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" n="5">
            <head style="text-align:center" rend="bold">Jewish squires and estate tenants in East <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs>.</head>
            <p>
               In a recently published book about the circumstances of the squires in East <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs> I noticed several interesting bits of information about the Jewish involvement 
               in estate ownership as owners of tenants as well as owners and tenants of brandy distilleries. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The book’s author, a Ruthenian, mainly addresses 15 East Galician districts where mainly Ruthenians live. He proves that of the 477 farms situated in these districts, 42 % of these are owned<pb/> by tenants. This means 
               the owners do not maintain the farms on their own, but leased the harvest to a third person. In the districts of <rs type="place"><ref source="place160">Podolia</ref></rs>, 57 % are owned by tenants, in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place161">Złotów</ref></rs> district 36 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place150">Husiatyn</ref></rs> district 33 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place162">Zalishchyky</ref></rs> 
               district 80 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> district 71 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place164">Kamianka-Buzka</ref></rs> district 62 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs> 
               district 86 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs> district 81 %, and so on. Those tenants are mainly Jewish, around 69 %. The writer thinks the reason for this is that Jews pay more 
               rent than Christians. For example, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs> district, Jewish tenants pay 24 crowns for a yoke of land while Christian ones only pay 22. In the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place167">Pidhaitsi</ref></rs> district Jews pay 21 crowns for a yoke while Christians pay 17, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs> the Jews pay 24, 
               Christians 19, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> district, the Jews 20, the Christians 13, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs> the Jews 22, the 
               Christians only 9. The Christian tenants of the archbishop’s lands which are not to be rented out to a Jew, do not fear Jewish competition. Therefore, they only pay crowns for a yoke. 
            </p>
            <p>
               So, 69 % of the tenants are Jewish while there are far less Jewish landlords. From 161 landlords in the aforementioned districts, only 24 are Jewish, or 21 %. Most Jewish landlords, 26 % are in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs> district, the least Jewish are found in <rs type="place"><ref source="place160">Podolia</ref></rs>, 12 %. It’s exactly the opposite for the tenants: 
               most of them live in <rs type="place"><ref source="place160">Podolia</ref></rs>. 
            </p>
            <p>
               If we add up landlords and tenants as one category, 159 out of 343 are Jewish, or 46 % - in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place169">Berezhany</ref></rs> district 40 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs>
               district 41 %, and in <rs type="place"><ref source="place160">Podolia</ref></rs> 58 %.
            </p>
            <p>
               However, there are two districts where the percentage of Jews is even bigger in the farming industry. Namely in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place162">Zalishchyky</ref></rs> district with 80 % and in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place167">Pidhaitsi</ref></rs> district 61 %. Furthermore there are 53 % in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place170">Zboriv</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place150">Husiatyn</ref></rs>,
               and the <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs> district, 50 % in <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs>, 
               44 % in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place171">Skalat</ref></rs> district, and in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place172">Horodok</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place173">Busk</ref></rs>, 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place164">Kamianka-Buzka</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> as well as 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place174">Vinnytsia</ref></rs> districts 27 %. 
           </p>
            <p>
               These have 76 % of all farms of the <rs type="place"><ref source="place162">Zalishchyky</ref></rs> district in their possession, 57 % of the farms in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place167">Pidhaitsi</ref></rs> 
               district, 50 % of <rs type="place"><ref source="place170">Zboriv</ref></rs>, 41 - 46 % of <rs type="place"><ref source="place171">Skalat</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs>, 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place150">Husiatyn</ref></rs>, and <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> districts, 30 - 39 % in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place161">Złotów</ref></rs>,  <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place174">Vinnytsia</ref></rs>, 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs>, and <rs type="place"><ref source="place164">Kamianka-Buzka</ref></rs> district, 21 % in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place172">Horodok</ref></rs>
               district, and 16 % in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place173">Busk</ref></rs> district.
            </p>
            <p>
               In four districts, there are only Jewish tenants but not a single landlord. Namely in the districts of <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs>,
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place164">Kamianka-Buzka</ref></rs>, and <rs type="place"><ref source="place172">Horodok</ref></rs>. The biggest number of Jewish landlords, 28 %, are to be found in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place171">Skalat</ref></rs> district. This district is the only one where a Jewish landlord possessed over 5000 yoke of farmland. In the <rs type="place"><ref source="place170">Zboriv</ref></rs> 
               district, there are 27 % Jewish landlords, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> 20 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place167">Pidhaitsi</ref></rs> 19 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place161">Złotów</ref></rs>
               15 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place150">Husiatyn</ref></rs> 12 %, and in <rs type="place"><ref source="place173">Busk</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs>,
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place162">Zalishchyky</ref></rs>, and <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs> 1 - 6 %.
            </p>
            <p>
               If we add up all goods which are owned by Jews and the goods which Jews have leased, then Jewish people have <cb/> 63 % in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place162">Zalishchyky</ref></rs> district, in 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place170">Zboriv</ref></rs> 49 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place150">Husiatyn</ref></rs> 41 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place167">Pidhaitsi</ref></rs>
               40 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place171">Skalat</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs>, and <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs>
               39 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place174">Vinnytsia</ref></rs> 30 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place173">Busk</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place161">Złotów</ref></rs>,
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place172">Horodok</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place164">Kamianka-Buzka</ref></rs>, and 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs> 3 - 17 %.
            </p>
            <p>
               These are the numbers we get if woods are included in the goods. However, if we only count the fields in the farming business, one finds that Jews use an even bigger percentage of the land. Namely, 
               in in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place162">Zalishchyky</ref></rs> district 87 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place165">Budaniv</ref></rs> district 59 %, in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place170">Zboriv</ref></rs> district 55 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place167">Pidhaitsi</ref></rs> district 54 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place166">Mykulyntsi</ref></rs>
               district 48 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place150">Husiatyn</ref></rs> district 44 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> 40 %. In <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs>,
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place174">Vinnytsia</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place168">Przemyśl</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place164">Kamianka-Buzka</ref></rs>, 
               and <rs type="place"><ref source="place171">Skalat</ref></rs> 31 - 36 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place161">Złotów</ref></rs> 22 %, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place172">Horodok</ref></rs>
               19 %, and in <rs type="place"><ref source="place173">Busk</ref></rs> 8 %. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Finally, it is important to mention that most of the brandy distilleries are in Jewish ownership. Therefore, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place169">Berezhany</ref></rs> 56 % of all 
               distilleries belong to Jews, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place160">Podolia</ref></rs> districts 64 %, in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place161">Złotów</ref></rs> district 92 %, and in 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place163">Kosiv</ref></rs> 100 %. This means that all six distilleries in the district are run by Jews.
            </p>
            <p>
               According to these statistics, one might believe that the Jews in East <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs> are very rich and everyone is well off. In reality, poverty is dire and only a very small part is wealthy.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" n="6">
            <head style="text-align:center" rend="bold">The world war.</head>
            <p>
               Lately, rarely any news of the Russo-Japanese war has been reported. As the first Japanese victories at sea have destroyed the Russian force, the Japanese now control the marines and can do whatever 
               they want there. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> has almost completely withdrawn, the main military quarters in the harbour city of <rs type="place"><ref source="person083">Port Arthur</ref></rs>
               - which the Japanese have besieged - have been dissolved and moved it to the city of <rs type="place"><ref source="place175"><hi rend="bold">Harbin</hi></ref></rs> which is several kilometres away 
               from the sea. Now, the Japanese sent their military to <rs type="place"><ref source="place022">Korea</ref></rs> - but until a bigger army is formed there and until they come in contact with the 
               Russians again, meaning the first battle on land, it will still take some time. News from the East-Asian battlefield is therefore not particularly interesting. 
            </p>
            <p>
               However, the world’s interest shifts to other nooks. There might be a war breaking out between <rs type="place"><ref source="place112">Bulgaria</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place075">Turkey</ref></rs>, 
               in which <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs> would be involved. Some even say that <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> has already given the order to
               mobilise the military. Officially it is still denied. But it is known that it has to be denied officially as to keep it a secret - it can still be the truth. - <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>
               will certainly not be happy that <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> is intervening without their approval and will occupy Macedonia. It <pb/>
            </p> 
            <p>
               has however drawn heavily on its ressources because of the war with <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and cannot be bothered with it. But it has been said that 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place040">Italy</ref></rs> will join forces with <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> in that case and go against <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs>. 
               In this case we would also have an <hi rend="italic">Austrian-Italian</hi> war as well. <rs type="place"><ref source="place010">Germany</ref></rs> also does not want to watch from afar but 
               wants to help <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>, only watching for the right opportunity. Also the French people are starting to get worked up and demand that 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place045">France</ref></rs> should prepare for war in case <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> and America are planning to support 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and support <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> in that case.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> in turn threatens that if <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> will not stop supporting 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> it will go to war with <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> on the Indian border. 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place075">Turkey</ref></rs> is determined to not sit still anymore if <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> 
               is to occupy <rs type="place"><ref source="place081">Macedonia</ref></rs>. Unlike when <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> took 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place142">Bosnia</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place075">Turkey</ref></rs> also gathered its military on the 
               Bosnian border to prepare for war.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs> is temporarily still calm and does not want to interfere in the Russo-Japanese war. However, the 
               Chinese government threatens to reach for its arms in case foreign military would cross the borders to defend itself.
            </p>
            <p>
               The world is moving towards a big <hi rend="italic">world  war</hi>: war between <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> and 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>; <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> against <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs>;
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place010">Germany</ref></rs>, and <rs type="place"><ref source="place045">France</ref></rs>
               against <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>; <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> and 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place008">America</ref></rs>; <rs type="place"><ref source="place112">Bulgaria</ref></rs> with 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place075">Turkey</ref></rs>; <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> 
               against <rs type="place"><ref source="place112">Bulgaria</ref></rs> in <rs type="place"><ref source="place075">Turkey</ref></rs>; <rs type="place"><ref source="place040">Italy</ref></rs>
               and <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs>.
            </p>
            <p>
               What will be the end of war? - Who could possibly know that now! In any case, big things are happening. 
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" n="7">
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">The war
               <lb/>between <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               The latest news of the battlefield concern mostly the movements of both militaries. The Russians try with all their might to bring as much as possible of their military 
               to the battlefield in <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs>. Admittedly, <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> is alone as it 
               does not have any military, weapons, or rations in Manchuria. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> has announced that it will still take time until 
               a battle would start. For the time being, <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> has moved its main quarters from the port city of <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs> 
               deep into the land into the city of <rs type="place"><ref source="place175"><hi rend="italic">Harbin</hi></ref></rs>. The Russians avoid any confrontations with the 
               Japanese and apply the same tactics as in the war against <rs type="person"><ref source="person066">Napoleon</ref></rs> in 1812. They lured him deep into the country 
               before destroying all military connections and attacking him. Whether it will be a success, remains a big question. Today’s connections are different than <cb/>100 years ago. 
               Back then it was happening far away from its own country, <rs type="place"><ref source="place139">Prussia</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> 
               helped <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>, and it was a harsh winter as well. All these things contributed to <rs type="person"><ref source="person066">Napoleon</ref></rs>'s 
               defeat. - Now we’re moving towards summer and <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> is certainly closer to its own country, it won’t let 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> cut the connection so easily. And after all, <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> 
               is only interested in exiling <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> from <rs type="place"><ref source="place022">Korea</ref></rs> and 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs>. If this goal is reached, <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> will settle down 
               in both countries and will not strive to chase <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> further. Furthermore, it is uncertain whether 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>’s plans will succeed.
               
ß            </p>
            <p>
               The fact is that <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> admitting that it is not prepared for the war reveals the whole organisation 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> functions as. For months now, the whole world has known that a war will break out - 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> did not know that and did not prepare for war. Whether it is possible to make up for it 
               remains a big question. <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> strives to sever connections and has already managed to break the 
               Manchuarian train tracks in several places. If the train system is damaged badly, sending military troops to <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs> 
               won’t be an easy task. 
            </p> 
            <p>
               Currently, it seems the sky is also at war with <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>; a quote seems to come true: "Also from the 
               heavens the stars fought from their courses". - The train with which <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> is sending its military to 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place136">East Asia</ref></rs> is breached by <rs type="place"><ref source="place176">Lake Baikal</ref></rs> with a width 
               of 40 verst [0.66 mile or 1.06 km]. In the winter, the lake is frozen solid and can hold heavy loads. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> 
               built tracks on the ice and let the train run over the lake. When heavy winds arose, the ice dispersed which caused people, carts, and goods to tumble 
               into the waters without a chance of saving them.
            </p>
            <p>   
               A second similar misfortune happened to <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>. A Russian ship wanted to lay mines into the water in 
               order for Japanese ships to trigger them and be destroyed when they wanted to reach the shore. Meanwhile a mine exploded while the preparations were 
               happening and destroyed <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>’s own ship.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> will certainly also have to alter their plans because of <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>’s 
               new tactics. It has to send their military through other ways into <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs>. The movements of the 
               Japanese military are held in secrecy and nobody knows where <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> wants to depose their military. 
               Preliminarily, it cannot be said for certain when the first battle on land will take place.
            </p>
            <p>
               For now, the Japanese control the sea, they block the harbour of <rs type="place"><ref source="person083">Port Arthur</ref></rs> and bomb the fortress there. 
               They have already tried a few times to conquer the city, but so far they have not managed to do so. One time, they even lost four ships. But this does not stop 
               them from pursuing their plans further. <rs type="place"><ref source="person083">Port Arthur</ref></rs> is a strong fortress and if it falls in Japanese hands, 
               they will have a great advantage. 
            </p>
            <p>   
               According to some news, <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> allowed Cossacks to enter <rs type="place"><ref source="place022">Korea</ref></rs> 
               which rode through the land to take some Japanese captive if they crossed their paths. 
            </p>
            <p>  
               The Russian battleships in <rs type="place"><ref source="place082">Vladivostok</ref></rs> still remain in the harbour and are afraid to venture out as the Japanese 
               battleships are stationed close to the harbour.
            </p>
            <p>[6]</p>
            <p>
               A prove how negligent the Russian military is might be this fact: while the Japanese battleship fired at <rs type="place"><ref source="place83">Port Arthur</ref></rs>, 
               destroying several ships, the Russian marine officers were visiting the circus and were entertained.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs>’s stance is not certain yet. <rs type="place"><ref source="place008">America</ref></rs> asked all forces to 
               guarantee <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs>’s neutrality. This means that both countries in this war should not penetrate the Chinese border. 
               Every country agreed with this proposal, even <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> - only <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> hesitates giving an answer.
            </p>
            <p>   
               The Chinese government proclaimed to intervene in war if anybody crosses the border or if the Chinese royal tombs in the city of <rs type="place"><ref source="place177">Mukden</ref></rs> 
               should be defiled. <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs> would probably join <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>’s forces. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> 
               demanded to lend military forces from <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs>, which should keep guard of the Manchurian trains. <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs> 
               answered that <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> has not trusted the Chinese military in times of peace and should not start believing in it now in times of 
               war. - Meanwhile the Chinese military is working with <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and helps destroy the railroads. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The Russian government revoked the command over the Russian army in <rs type="place"><ref source="place136">East Asia</ref></rs> from admiral <rs type="person"><ref source="person067">Alekseyev</ref></rs> 
               and gave order to the minister of war, <rs type="person"><ref source="person068">Kuropatktin</ref></rs>. The military force has already been dispatched to <rs type="place"><ref source="place178">Siberia</ref></rs>.
            </p>
            <p> 
               Meanwhile, there are great preparations for a <hi rend="italic">revolution</hi>. The people in <rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs> is particularly uneasy. 
            </p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <p>
               As our readers should be able to trace every detail of the war, they should also know about every region where the battles will take place. We will publish a booklet explaining 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place022">Korea</ref></rs>, and Asian <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>; 
               every mountain, every city, important railroads, statistical information and so on. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The booklet will cost 10 kreutzer. One can also send stamps. Larger purchases are granted discounts.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="8">
            
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Mobilisation in <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs>.</hi></head>
            <p>
               Despite officially denying that <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs> is mobilising its military, the mobilisation might still be happening according 
               to different cities.
            </p>
            <p>
               For example, <rs type="place"><ref source="place179">Stanislau</ref></rs> reports from railway officials who are back-up officers who have received conscription letters to report 
               to their regiments in <rs type="place"><ref source="place026">Bohemia</ref></rs>. On the 22nd of this month, four wagons with military cooks and their supplies left from 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place179">Stanislau</ref></rs> to <rs type="place"><ref source="place008">Hungary</ref></rs>.<cb/> The cavalry has also received orders to prepare 
               their horses - even the sick ones who have been handed over to private persons to nurse them. Several Bohemian cities have also reported similar procedures which hints at serious matters. 
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="9">
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">News.</hi><lb/>Jewish News.</head>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place179">Stanislau</ref></rs>). <rs type="person"><ref source="person069">Rabbi Ari Leib Horowitz of Stryi</ref></rs> has unanimously been elected as the Rabbi of our community.
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place007">Vienna</ref></rs>). The amount of Jews being baptised grows bigger year after year. In 1897, 453 Jews have been baptised, 265 men and 188 women; 
               in 1898 - 434, 252 men and 182 women; in 1899 - 482, 280 men and 202 women; in 1900 - 559, 315 men and 244 women; in 1901 - 551, 313 men and 238 women.
            </p>
            <p>   
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place030">Budapest</ref></rs>). The emperor gifted <rs type="person">Almana Stein</rs>, the president of the Jewish orphanage for boys, the Golden Cross of 
               Merit with the crown in honour of her beneficence. 
            </p>
            <p>   
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place035">Bukarest</ref></rs>). In the month of July, in the city <rs type="place"><ref source="place180">Iași</ref></rs>, a four year old boy has gone missing. 
               Into a field. The Romanians <rs type="person">Jakob Zigrean</rs> and <rs type="person">Martin Darlatzu</rs> tormented the child badly. They sat him on an ant hill and put pieces of broken glass into his mouth. The poor 
               parents were searching for the child everywhere when <rs type="person">Darlatzu</rs> told them that the child was in a hole in the woods, from which he was rescued, barely alive. 
               The court sentenced <rs type="person">Jakob Zigrean</rs> to five months. The other accomplices were acquitted of a charge. 
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs>). Bad times are coming for the Jewish community. The government, who treated them graciously until now, changed its proceedings. 
               First, the senate passed a law that baptised Jews should be noted as former Jews in their passports as well as add their former Jewish name. Because of this they can be recognised as former Jews 
               everywhere immediately. - Now the senate passed another law that baptised Jews can live anywhere they want in <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> only if they had the right 
               as Jews already, meaning they were learned merchants who paid first class taxes and similar people. If they could not live anywhere they wanted before, they will not gain the right by baptism. 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place034">Israel</ref></rs>, even though he sinned, is <rs type="place"><ref source="place034">Israel</ref></rs>!
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place181">Stockholm</ref></rs>). The royal library is in possession of a Bible worth 400,000 marks. The Bible contains 160 pages, measuring 80 cm in height and 67 cm 
               in width. The Bible is illustrated with very beautiful pictures. The letters are 1 cm in height and the book cover is made out of oak wood. The entire Bible weighs 60 pounds. 
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place096">New York</ref></rs>). With the help of the Jewish yearbook, we found out the number of Jews living in <rs type="place"><ref source="place008">North America</ref></rs> in all of the <pb/> 
            </p>
            <p>[7]</p>
            <p>
               52 provinces. 1,127,268 Jews (may their number increase) live in the <rs type="place"><ref source="place094">United States of America</ref></rs>. Most of them live in <rs type="place"><ref source="place096">New York</ref></rs>, 
               more than half a million. Other big communities are located in <rs type="place"><ref source="place182">Chicago</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place183">Philadelphia</ref></rs>, and 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place184">Baltimore</ref></rs>. 
            </p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">The resolutions of the Conference regarding the Jewish question in <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>.</hi></head>
            <p>
               As we have already reported, the Russian government convened a conference of all provinces to discuss the Jewish question in <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>. They discussed whether Jewish laws should 
               be alleviated. The conference is now over and they agreed on the following resolutions: 
            </p>
            <p>
               1) The law, disallowing Jews not to live 50 verst away from the border is to be alleviated <hi rend="italic">immediately</hi>. The law was passed to break off smuggles of uncostumed 
               merchandise, as was argued. But it is evident now that the smuggling got worse from that point on. The government also sent telegrams to all provinces ordering to announce that Jews 
               can live along the borders again. 
            </p>
            <p>
               2) The laws not allowing Jews to live in villages are to be repealed. The provinces where Jews are allowed to live, should also be allowed to live in villages, but they are not allowed 
               to purchase land. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Some might argue that the Russian government wants to start treating Jewish people better, but that is not true. At the same time, the Russian government commanded to cast out all Jews 
               living in <rs type="place"><ref source="place178">Siberia</ref></rs>. The government is probably afraid that Jewish people will ally with <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> 
               in the current war with <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>. And because the military transport is sent with the Siberian railroad Jews are getting expelled. The 
               whole world was shocked by this current act of violence. Jewish people in <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs> are demonstrating heavily and want to hand over a 
               protest via the English government. 
            </p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Postbox.</hi></head>
            <p>
               To <hi rend="italic"><rs type="person">Rabbi J. B. Bm.</rs></hi> The rabbi is not obliged to present the marriage documents to the register administrator. (Decree of the  K.K. prefecture).
            </p>
            <p>  
               To register administrator <hi rend="italic"><rs type="person">Jakob B.</rs></hi> It is not sufficient that the parties are personally known, but have to verify their personal abilities to marry. 
            </p>
            <p>
               To the liquor lessee <hi rend="italic"><rs type="person">B. W.</rs></hi>: the authorised sellers of licensed liquor are forbidden to fill the barrels in front of customers as the retailer with 
               their beverages. (Prefecture decree).
            </p>
         </div>
         <cb/>
         <div type="ads">
            <p>The editor does not take responsibility for the advertisements in this paper.</p>
            <div type="ad">
               <head><hi rend="bold">The sugar refinery of <rs type="place"><ref source="place060">Przeworsk</ref></rs></hi></head>
               <p>
                  Has immensely scaled up its sugar production for 1904 and recommends every variety to extremely low prices.
                  <lb/>You can get various useful instructions for register handlers, head of cultural affairs, private individuals, etc. at different prices.
                  <lb/><rs type="person">S. Weinstock</rs>, in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place185">Rzeznika</ref></rs> 5.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="ad">
               <head>
                  <lb/><hi rend="bold">Coffee!</hi>
                  <lb/><hi rend="italic>">All natural!</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  Also less than 5 kg, payment on delivery, prepaid, postage.
               </p>
               <table rows="3" cols="2">
                  <row role="data">
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place"><ref source="place054">Santos</ref></rs> Coffee á 1,20 guilders</cell>
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place"><ref source="place055">Puerto Rico</ref></rs> Pearl á 1,23 guilders</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row role="data">
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place"><ref source="place056">Cuba</ref></rs>     "    "  1,46 "</cell>
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place"><ref source="place057">Ceylon</ref></rs>     "     "  1,68 "  </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row role="data">
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place"><ref source="place057">Ceylon</ref></rs>  "   "    1,62  "</cell>
                     <cell role="data">Gold <rs type="place"><ref source="place058">Java</ref></rs>   "   "   1,45 "</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
               <lb/>
               <p>
                  Free samle and payment on delivery
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs type="person">Berger Ernö</rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place058">Fuime</ref></rs>.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="ad">
               <head><hi rend="bold">Fine tea</hi></head>
               <p>
                  <lb/>If you want to drink pure, unadulterated tea, write to the address below,
                  <lb/>1 kg fine, pure tea only 6 crowns.
                  <lb/>There is also tea costing 3 to 10 crowns per kg.
                  <lb/>Sample for free and prepaid.
                  <lb/><rs type="person">L. Aperman</rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs> <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs>.
                  <lb/>Thee &amp; Caffe Lager.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="ad" style="text-align:center">
               <p>Bank and exchange business
               <lb/>ROHAYTN &amp; ULAM
               <lb/><foreign xml:lang="de"><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lemberg</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place186">Syxtuskagasse</ref></rs> 8.</foreign>
               <lb/>Buying and selling all kinds of
               <lb/>Effects, lotteries, and coins.
               <lb/>Lottery available in cheap installments.
               <lb/>At request, a lottery calendar for 1904
               <lb/>can be given for free.
               <lb/>Easy, low-interest loans available.</p>
            </div>
      </div>
      <div type="footer" style="one column" n="1">
         <p>
            <foreign xml:lang="de">
               <lb/>Herausgeber und verantwortlicher Redact. <rs type="person">OSIAS H. WILF</rs> recte Weinstock
               <lb/>Druck von <rs type="person">E. Salat</rs> Witwe des <rs type="person">U.W. Salat</rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lemberg</ref></rs> <rs type="place"><ref source="place065">Kasimirgasse 35</ref></rs>
            </foreign>
         </p>   
         <p style="text-align:center">[8]</p>
        </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>








