<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" source="1904-03-11.xml">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="s">The Genuine Jew - 1904-03-11</title>
            <title level="a">1904-03-11</title>
            <author>Multiple Authors</author>
            <editor>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </editor>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>TGJ</edition>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Translation</resp>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </respStmt>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </publisher>
            <pubPlace>Vienna</pubPlace>
            <date when="2025">2025</date>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">
                  <p>You are free to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any medium or
                     format; adapt — remix, transform, and build upon the material for any purpose,
                     even commercially.</p>
                  <p>The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license
                     terms. Under the following terms:</p>
                  <p>Attribution — You must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license,
                     and indicate if changes were made. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but
                     not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use. No
                     additional restrictions — You may not apply legal terms or technological
                     measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license
                     permits.</p>
                  <p>Notices:</p>
                  <p>You do not have to comply with the license for elements of the material in the
                     public domain or where your use is permitted by an applicable exception or
                     limitation. No warranties are given. The license may not give you all of the
                     permissions necessary for your intended use. For example, other rights such as
                     publicity, privacy, or moral rights may limit how you use the material.</p>
               </licence>
               <p>Copyright 2021 Österreichische Nationalbibliothek</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>A</country>
                  <settlement>Vienna</settlement>
                  <repository>Austrian National Library</repository>
                  <collection/>
               </msIdentifier>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when-iso="1904-03-11">1904-03-11</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Sonngasse 27, Lemberg</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile source="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/anno?aid=emj&amp;datum=19040311">
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="1">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|1|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="2">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|2|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="3">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|3|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="4">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|4|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="1">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|5|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="2">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|6|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="3">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|7|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="4">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040311|8|100.0|0"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="heading" n="1" style="one column">

            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">1.Jahrgang Nr. 8 </foreign> 1st year</p>
         </div>
         <div type="title" n="1">
            <head>
               <hi rend="bold">The Geniune Jew</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Organ for Yiddish matters</p>
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">DER WAHRE JUDE</foreign></p>
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">Organ für die Gesammtinteressen des Judenthums</foreign></p>
         </div>
         <div type="editorial" n="1" style="two columns">
            <cb n="1"/>
            <table rows="4" cols="2">
               <head>The Geniune Jew costs</head>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">In <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs></cell>
                  <cell role="data">Abroad</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 12 Kronen</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 20 Francs</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 6 "</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 10 "</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 3.50 "</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 5.50 "</cell>
               </row>
            </table>
            <p><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>,<date when-iso="1904-03-11"> March 11th 1904</date></p>
            <cb n="2"/>
            <p>
               <lb/>Adverts are cheaply calculated <lb/>All letters and money send to: <lb/><foreign
                  xml:lang="de">Redaction "Der wahre Jude",<rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>, <rs
                     type="place">Sonnengasse 27</rs></foreign>
               <lb/>The Genuine Jew is published every Tuesday and Friday <lb/><foreign
                  xml:lang="de"><rs type="place">Lemberg</rs>, <date when-iso="1904-03-11">den 11.März 1904</date></foreign>.</p>
         </div>
         <lb/>
         <div n="1">
            <p>
               We ask our subscribers who paid for the “Genuine Jew” when it was published only once a week, to please send money to add to their subscription according to the current price of the newspaper. For those who do not 
               remargin, we will deduct the difference from their current subscription. This means those who subscribed for half a year will receive the paper for only four months. The same applies to yearly and quarterly subscribers. 
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:right">- The editorial office.</p>
         </div>
         <div n="2">
            <head>The tsar weeps.</head>
            <p style="text-align:right">The Holy One, Blessed is He, does not exact retribution from a nation until its time is up. (<ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q927314">Tractate Sotah</ref>, Chapter 9)</p>
            <p>
               And the tsar weeps! He is experiencing the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q1093647">Fast of Esther</ref> and the emperor of <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> is experiencing Purim.
            </p>
            <p> 
               The ruler of over 130 million people in <rs type="place"><ref source="place100">Europe</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place024">Asia</ref></rs> is weeping in his winter palace, as telegrams report from 
               every corner, because he is helpless, like a child. He is sitting, wringing his hands and sobs bitter tears like the Jewish widows and orphans of the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q1814439">Kishinev pogroms</ref>.
            </p>
            <p> 
               Yes, the tsar is weeping.
            </p><cb/>
            <p>
               It has not been a year yet, since the tragedy on the eighth day of Passover. There are still five weeks to go until the first anniversary. But the tsar has soon shed as many tears because of his first defeat in battle like 
               the Jews did for those corpses, how could he not cry? His best ships lay shattered by Japanese cannons and Russian gunpowder, Russian soldiers are being taken prisoners by <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> 
               while travelling, and hundreds of soldiers die of starvation or freeze to death in the frozen wasteland of <rs type="place"><ref source="place178">Siberia</ref></rs>. The Russian battleships are more sealed off for Jews than 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place151">Moscow</ref></rs> even. And the Russian soldiers cannot comfort themselves as between the corpses on the battleships are no sacrifices made by Jews. The tsar is weeping remembering that 
               the hundreds of dead and wounded on his ships are all Russian. He also knows that on those ships that have been shattered by Russian bombs along with 300 people is the number of corpses five times more Russians than Jews in the 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place015">Kishinev</ref></rs> pogroms and <rs type="place"><ref source="place016">Gomel</ref></rs> altogether! How can he not weep?
            </p>
            <p>
               And the tsar is weeping. He cries because of his country’s disgrace. He cries because of his crown’s failure. He cries because of his enemies’ vengeance all around the world, he cries because of his horrible mistakes. He is now 
               learning something the scientific world has known for at least 20 years: Nowadays, not the strongest nation wins the war, but the most progressive one. The brain is worth more on the battlefield than the fist. The truth is
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="information" style="one column">
            <p>We ask the subscribers of מחזיקי הדת (upholders of religion) and קול מחזיקי הדת (the
               voice of the upholders of religion) to send every letter and money to this
               address:</p>
            <p>OSIAS H. WILF, <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">LEMBERG</ref></rs>
               <ref source="place003"><rs type="place">Sonnengasse 27</rs></ref>.</p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[1]</p>
         </div>
         <pb/>
         <div n="2">
            <p>
               that <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> has more soldiers, but <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> has better brains and skillful fingers. A good general today does not look for hundreds 
               of thousands of men with broad shoulders and iron limbs. He needs carefully assembled thousand intelligent men. It is very easy, because the man who stands behind the cannon on a ship or holding a weapon in his hand - this shooter 
               should not be a strong man. He should only have a sharp eye to aim, stable hands to shoot, and a swift motion to dodge the enemy’s fire. Didn’t <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> prove that a small torpedo boat, 
               a little bigger than a <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q611564">skiff</ref>, but assembled with wisdom, is able to sink a battleship? Didn’t the Russians themselves prove how one wrong manoeuvre can cause the best ships to 
               commit suicide by their own bombs.
            </p>
            <p>
               And the tsar weeps living with his mistakes with the war he wages. He thinks that it is still working like it did earlier as the sword, the bayonet, and the fist met in war. Nowadays, these old ways of battling are only seen in theatre, 
               but not on the battlefield where a weak soldier with rheumatism in his feet can carry a small package in his coat pocket which can destroy a whole regiment.
            </p>
            <p>
               But more than anything, the tsar weeps because he now witnesses God’s finger and he knows that <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> is nothing more than a rod (scepter) to punish the land for the pogroms. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The Talmud scholars say: "The Holy One, Blessed is He, does not take revenge from the nation until its measure is full (<ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q927314">Tractate</ref> Sotah, chapter 9)." That means: The Lord punishes the 
               nation as soon as the barrel of bad news is overflowing”. That is the historical truth for every tyrannical government through the times. The true angel of death of the Russian throne is not <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>, 
               but the destruction of <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q165420">Pleven</ref> which filled up the barrel of Russia’s rage caused by the pogroms, which upset the whole world and cost <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> 
               the last bit of sympathy. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The tsar weeps and the Russian government asks for donations for a new fleet like the Jews asked for donation. But we fared better as the whole world cried with us while the tsar’s tears found no echo. The world smiles, the world enjoys itself 
               as <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> receives its punishment. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="person">S. Selikowitz</rs>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" n="3">
            <p>
               A Jewish newspaper which is published in America prints an interesting picture: the destroyed school in <rs type="place"><ref source="place015">Chișinău</ref></rs>, pictured from one side, the beadle of <rs type="person">Rabbi Moshe</rs> lays in 
               blood and holds a torn Torah scroll. On the other side is the harbour of <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs> with destroyed battleships, the strongholds shot into pieces, cannons, and dead soldiers. The picture is called 
               “An eye for an eye” and below the following poem is written: 
            </p><cb/>
            <p>
               There in the school of <rs type="place"><ref source="place015">Kishinev</ref></rs>, everything is broken,
               <lb/>There lies the beadle of <rs type="person">Rabbi Moshe</rs>, violence and fear!
               <lb/>He lies in a pool of blood, beaten to death,
               <lb/>Beside the school, next to a torn up Torah scroll!
               <lb/>There in <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs>, a harbour in the depth,
               <lb/>The Jewish God performed a pogrom;
               <lb/><rs type="person"><ref source="person042">Nikolas</ref></rs>’ heroes and greatest ships,
               <lb/>Lay there on the threshold of the abyss!
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="4">
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">The luxury.<lb/>(Second article)</hi></head>
            <p>
               In my first article about luxury in “The Genuine Jew” I described briefly in which ways luxury is a blight of Galician Jewry. Whether the article has already changed something, if it opened someone’s eyes is to be debated. The public is entrenched in bitter 
               and heavy suffering that it does not know where it is hurting. And as there are several who feel and know how harmful it is, they need to shut up. They are afraid to say something, they know that they want to scratch their eyes out when seeing the femininity 
               of the Jewish daughters. What are they supposed to do? They watch everything in chopped motions and stay silent.
            </p>
            <p>
               To remedy this, they have to look for a way to enlighten those who are addicted to fashion how bad it is for them. Only saying or writing it once will not convince them. One has to say it a lot, to scream a lot and scream loudly until they understand it. Then 
               it will be achieved to enlighten the populace. Perhaps God will have mercy!
            </p>
            <p>
               Lately we are being suppressed from every side, meeting our needs has become difficult or it is completely taken away even. The neighbours are looking for ways to take away the Jewish livelihoods with “village collections”, with “cooperative societies”, 
               and so on. The number of antisemites grow continuously to every side, their wants do as well. They do not want to lose against others. Furthermore, we Jews are searching for new taxes to pay as well. Under no circumstances can we let it happen that a 
               government wants a tax of several guilds from every Jewish wedding. With what force will this be implemented? It will be recorded, protested, called upon. Every Jewish as well as Jewish-adjacent newspaper will write lengthy articles. Unbelievable! Has 
               this not been heard before! We are also taxing ourselves high. Every smaller wedding receives 20 - 30 telegrams, the opulent weddings receive 100 - 200 and more. They make a whole fuss out of it, but what for? Does it make any sense? It is very costly. Jews 
               do not know where to put their money!
            </p>
            <p>
               The high valued virtue of “hospitality” has also disappeared from a lot of Jewish houses because of luxury. In earlier times as Jews had enough riches with 2 - 3 rooms, the furniture was simple, no rugs on the floor. A person entered the house, greeted the 
               guest warmly; he did not ruin the furniture, did not soil the rugs. On Sabbath people fought over having a poor person over for Sabbath, everyone wanted to provide their <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q211361">matzah</ref> and hospitality. These 
               days, our Jews became very<pb/> 
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">[2]</p>
            <p>
               different and with it the good Jewish customs. Nowadays after a wedding, they truly have many rags with thousand coins dowry. First, they rent a lovely apartment, 2 - 3 rooms with nice furniture, carpets and rugs as well as several other things. At that point 
               they have already spent a huge part of the dowry and have already stepped towards poverty. As soon as someone enters the door, he will be looked upon as a detrimental thing, he could ruin the chairs, soil the carpets. Later, when a daughter has grown up, raised 
               by today’s Zeitgeist, she will not like her own home. She would like to store everything anywhere. How can a Jew let someone in their home and who invites a poor person still?
            </p>
            <p>
               In previous times, when one met a poor man, one befriended him. He would have been treated friendly and brotherly, he was given the best meals. The poor man was satisfied and could forget his poverty a bit. He started to like the rich men, the landlords that 
               once he got him he told how the rich man treated him, how good these people are. This made a good impression on his children and they have become more humane as they realised that there are good people left in the world. These days, the poor man comes home and 
               recounts how badly he has been treated. He is planting misanthropy, spite, and despair in the young hearts of his children. Because of this the children will later in life, when they are older, be driven into useless and harmful tendencies which will neither 
               provide help or honour to them or their brothers.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="person">Shekel Hatismanichi</rs>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="5">
            <head style="text-align:center">Letters from <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>.</head>
            <p>
               It happened as we have predicted before: We turn up and right to listen to the speech of the throne for the parliament’s inauguration. The main venture of the government for this season is to put through a bill which should forbid workers to enter and unless the 
               government breaks up in the middle, this law is virtually certain. 
            </p>
            <p>
               In the meantime, the law’s details are not public yet. However, the newspapers which are close to the government and constantly know what they are talking about published the character of these new laws. It turns out that the government wants to make them very 
               strict. As the papers claim, that before immigrants are allowed to enter <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> they will have to provide: 
            </p>
            <list rend="numbered"> 
               <item>A valid passport issued by the countries they resided in before.</item> 
               <item>He must know how to read and write in the language of origin.</item>
               <item>He must have a certain amount of money and will have to explain how he plans on earning money.</item>
               <item>The immigrant has to be completely healthy.</item>
            </list> 
            <p>
               If the immigrant cannot satisfy the inspectors in these four points he will be sent back.
            </p>
            <p>
               But it does not end here. If the immigrant is lucky enough to be admitted into the country, they<cb/> are allowed to stay 3 - 5 days under police surveillance. If it turns out that an immigrant lives on welfare - except in times of sickness - or breaks a law, he 
               will immediately be sent back to the country of origin. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Those areas suffering or had suffered from an abundance of foreigners, is allowed to be classified as a forbidden areas, where foreign Jews are not allowed to live. 
            </p>
            <p>
               In order to protect it all, foreigners living in <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> have to report themselves to the police. No foreigner is allowed to move places without telling the police in order for the latter to know whether the 
               foreigner lives legally or illegally. 
            </p>
            <p>
               This is supposed to be the government’s plan; a “Jewish quarter” should be erected like the ones in <rs type="place"><ref source="place015">Russia</ref></rs>, but a little bit worse. First this should prevent new migrants from moving there and meeting the ones 
               already residing there. The new Jew should not be able to have job prospects and should not be able to find other Jews. And when they find stone instead of bread how would they be able to find work or an occupation in good Jewish neighbourhoods since the assaults 
               on Jews everywhere in the world and in <rs type="place"><ref source="place211">Ireland</ref></rs> in the last few weeks. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The rich Jews understand that the new legislation only targets Jews. They know it’s the result of a weak government which bends to the wishes of the British brothers to gain votes for the upcoming election. The Jews in high ranks do everything possible to prevent 
               the law from becoming so strict. If the law has to be passed it should at least be as mild as possible. One can only hope that until the law is passed, it will be altered a lot. In any case, it will be much stricter than the American immigration laws. The laws in 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place094">America</ref></rs> want to target only truly bad immigrants although good ones are also often affected. Nobody wants to exclude good workers. It is still mainly affecting the good ones to prevent fierce competition against 
               the domestic workers. 
            </p>
            <p>
               English citizens in some areas of <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs> took the minister’s advice to defend themselves from foreigners with their fists. In a particular London area, a gang has been formed to beat up every Jew they meet on the 
               street; Jewish workers have been pelted with stones on the way from and to work. Police are constantly not present to arrive at the scene once it is too late and the gang has dispersed already. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="person">Moishe Ben-Zvi</rs>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="6">
            <head style="text-align:center">The Austrian Imperial Assembly.</head>            
            <p>The Austrian parliament opened its doors again on Tuesday. Minister president <rs type="person"><ref source="person004">Dr. Koerber</ref></rs> held a great political speech in the first meeting. He reported about the war between <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> 
               and <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and noted that <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs> commiserates the war and will remain</p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">[3]</p>
            <p>
               strictly neutral - impartial to both parties. After that he discussed the <rs type="place"><ref source="place081">Balkan</ref></rs>’s state of affairs and said that any rumours about mobilisation of the Austrian army is false. He hopes to bring order to 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place075">Turkey</ref></rs> without war.
            </p>
            <p>
               Then he talked about the Austrian state of affairs. He announced that the government is planning to build an Italian university in the Tyrolean city of <rs type="place"><ref source="place212">Rovereto</ref></rs> and called upon the parliament to finally get to work 
               as the country is suffering greatly from the parliament’s inactivity to pass important legislation. Over 60 laws which have to be passed under § 14 lay in parliament gathering dust. Nobody can conclude new trade contracts, the new custom tariff has not been agreed 
               upon, the Compromise is hanging on thin threads. Subsequently the <rs type="person"><ref source="person004">minister president</ref></rs> urged the parliament to first conclude the new recruitment law. He does not expect for war to break out on the Balkan, but 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place025">Austria</ref></rs> has to be prepared for any eventualities. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The speech did not have a great impact. The <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q1713492">Young Czech Party</ref> is not willing to stop their obstruction. They requested to open the session over the minister president's speech to spend some days with it. 
               They also initiated some emergency motions which have to be managed first according to the rules of order. Therefore, the hope to debate the recruitment act is diminished. 
            </p>
            <p>
               During the second session, the minister president answered to the demands coming from the demonstrations between Germans and Czechs in <rs type="place"><ref source="place135">Prague</ref></rs> last Sunday. The Czechs do not permit German students to stroll through 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place135">Prague</ref></rs> with their colourful hats and ribbons. <rs type="place"><ref source="place135">Prague</ref></rs> is a Slavic city and must not be “colonised” by Germans. The Germans do not want to relent and that is why 
               Czechs and Germans clashed intensely last Sunday. The police and military had to intervene, several people were arrested, <rs type="place"><ref source="place135">Prague</ref></rs> looked like a revolution. The demonstrations happened again in the middle of the 
               week. The current situation is to be taken very seriously. The Czechs were not satisfied with the minister president’s answer and caused a scandal in parliament. They yelled, rattled, and whistled - like in bygone days. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Little hope remains that the parliament can truly return to doing serious work. The government either has to resign and a new one has to install peace and order; or the Imperial Assembly will be dissolved and new elections will be arranged. Maybe the new 
               parliament will be better than the old one.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="7">
            <head><hi rend="bold">News.<lb/>Jewish News.</hi></head>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place149">Krakow</ref></rs>). Six years ago, a Jewish girl with the name of <rs type="person">Rosa Bürger</rs> returned to <rs type="place"><ref source="place149">Krakow</ref></rs>. She came from the<cb/>town 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place213">Dołgie</ref></rs> and entered a monastery to prepare for her conversion. Her lover was a lesser clerk who promised to make her luckiest girl in the world if she gets baptised. Her parents, great 
               fallen people of the most beautiful families sacrificed themselves, sold out everything that was left in their homes from older times, they ruined their shops, were homeless for several years and knocked on the doors of Polish aristocrats - 
               the highest officers in <rs type="place"><ref source="place149">Krakow</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place007">Vienna</ref></rs>, but it was all for nothing. Everyone agreed and as soon as something happened, the nuns cheated 
               everyone. They sent the girl from city to city and no one found her until she returned to <rs type="place"><ref source="place149">Krakow</ref></rs>, already baptised and already married to the clerk. The parents became sick caused by shame 
               and resentment. Not long ago a woman from the same town was in the hospital. Family came to visit her. One time, everyone was at the sick woman’s bed and had a discussion. Suddenly, they heard horrible crying from another room and the voice 
               seemed very familiar. They look around and find a familiar travelling citizen lying in the bed and ripping her hair out. The people were afraid to go to this traveller, but she waved them over. As they were on her side, the woman poured out 
               her heart. She told them how she got sick because of her hardships and that she already received heart valves for her wails and lamentations. Her joy, she told them, has lasted less than a year. Soon her husband forgot her, spent time with 
               strangers and left her alone. Every day she had to work hard for one dry piece of bread, without a friendly word, without any friends, without any sunshine in her life. Soon her husband started drinking, always came home after half a night 
               of drinking and beat her up horribly. Finally, he was arrested because he stole money from his department and squandered it. Now, she was alone, poor, and forlorn; she didn’t even have a piece of bread. Once she got very sick, she had to be 
               admitted to the hospital otherwise she would have died from starvation. The Jewish women let her talk and promised her that as soon as she is healthy again, they will take her home with them back to her parents who will embrace her. However, 
               the other day a hospital nun entered the room to speak with the “Jewish woman” and she was moved to another room; the women do not know how or where she will end up.
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place030">Budapest</ref></rs>). Not long ago a great estate owner, even the richest owner in <rs type="place"><ref source="place009">Hungary</ref></rs>, died. In his will he bequeathed everything to the Hungarian 
               Academy on the condition that if <rs type="place"><ref source="place009">Hungary</ref></rs> will be in need after a hundred years, the goods shall be sold and used to finance a national guard. But Jews are not allowed to buy anything, not even 
               someone with a Jew in their family! (What a great philanthropist!)
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs>). In the town <rs type="place"><ref source="place214">Uman</ref></rs> the local school including its 64 Torah scrolls burnt down. The school
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">[4]</p><pb/>
            <p>
               
               was 700 years old and survived terrible times caused by the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q1569666">Haydamak</ref> <rs type="person"><ref source="person095">Gonta</ref></rs>, <rs type="person"><ref source="person096">Khmelnytsky</ref></rs>, 
               and <rs type="person"><ref source="person097">Zalizniak</ref></rs>.
            </p>
            <p>
               During <rs type="person"><ref source="person095">Gonta</ref></rs>’s time, the Haydamak occupied the big school in which Jewish women and children were hidden. As they saw that the Haydamak were not stopping causing the Jews to be in great danger, a Jew 
               called <rs type="person">Moishe Mocher</rs> stepped outside with a sword in his hands. Behind him emerged several Jews who managed to disperse the Haydamak. However, on the following day, they came back and brought a Harmat (cannon) with which they shot 
               the school to pieces and massacred the Jews. 
            </p>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place215">Kaunas</ref></rs>). More and more Jews are emigrating from here to <rs type="place"><ref source="place210">South Africa</ref></rs>. The local post office receives cash remittance sent by emigrants to their families 
               in <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> daily.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="8">
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Are the Japanese Jews?</hi></head>
            <p>
               A British writer has discovered that the Japanese descend from Jews. According to his historic research, 730 years before the general chronology (2634 years ago), a tribe from an unknown country arrived in <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> 
               under command of their leader [<rs type="person"><ref source="person098"><hi rend="italic">Hoshea</hi></ref></rs>, who reigned over Japan. His children as well continued watching over the country for 126 generations until today. [N.B. The first emperor of Japan 
               was <rs type="person"><ref source="person099">Jimmu</ref></rs>, not <rs type="person"><ref source="person098">Hoshea</ref></rs>, whose reign started 660 BC.] According to Jewish history, 2634 years ago, the king of <rs type="place"><ref source="place216">Assyria</ref></rs> 
               <rs type="person"><ref source="person100">Sargon II</ref></rs> occupied the Jewish land <rs type="place"><ref source="place217">Samaria</ref></rs> and banished the then king [<rs type="person"><ref source="person098"><hi rend="italic">Hoshea</hi></ref></rs>. There is 
               a photograph featuring the Jews travelling through the island of <rs type="place"><ref source="place218">Sakhalin</ref></rs> in a Japanese album. More Jews are gathered in front of the Jews marching into <rs type="person"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>. 
               King <rs type="person"><ref source="person098">Hoshea</ref></rs> drives a wagon, surrounded by his guards who are carrying two <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q2915196">Tablets of Stone</ref> with spears and flags. The English writer copied other 
               photographs as well which clearly show that Jews were in <rs type="person"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> before the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q223644">Destruction of the First Temple</ref> in <rs type="place"><ref source="place050">Jerusalem</ref></rs> 
               in 586 BCE. <rs type="person"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>’s sigil features a lion with twelve young lions and is very similar to the English sigil (as we know, the English claim that they descend from the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q1125226">Ten Lost Tribes</ref>). 
               Their sigil is a mark of Jakob and the twelve tribes. One can find people similar to Jews in the Japanese nobility, including the king and the princes. - If all of this is true, it is understandable why <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs> is 
               allied with <rs type="person"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> as they would be of one family. - It would be a great setback for <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> as Jews would bring about <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>'s fall.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="9">
            <head><hi rend="bold">Telegrams.<lb/>The war<lb/>Between <rs type="person"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs></hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               (<rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>). The Japanese ships which bombarded the port of <rs type="place"><ref source="place082">Vladivostok</ref></rs> on Sunday wanted to know how far the Russian ships reside in the harbour and where exactly 
               they are located. As the Russian battleships<cb/> didn’t return fire the Japanese were sure that the Russian ships were not in the harbour, but were waiting in the middle of the sea for Japanese steamboats delivering military and weapons. Therefore, the Japanese 
               headed out to the sea to find and destroy the Russian chips. If they succeed they would ensure even greater victory in <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs>.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>. It is being reported that Japanese battleships which bombarded <rs type="place"><ref source="place082">Vladivostok</ref></rs>, encountered Russian battleships and forced them to battle. The Japanese won greatly. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs>. The Japanese battleships bombarded <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs> again on Tuesday and Wednesday and caused great harm.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs>. The chaplain <rs type="person"><ref source="person101">John of Kronstadt</ref></rs> said that the war will last another 25 years - but <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> will win in the end. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place031">Berlin</ref></rs>. A military expert calculated the cost of supplying an army of 300,000 men in <rs type="place"><ref source="place136">East Asia</ref></rs>. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> 
               needs to send six trains with food there daily. The Siberian railway can currently drive nine trains daily, but not constantly because it is badly built and has only one set of rails. Two to three days the rails need to stay unoccupied for military transport. 
               Therefore, <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> can feed 300,000 men if necessary, but more than this is not possible. <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> on the other side is not far away from its country and can also 
               build a bigger army. It will therefore also be stronger on land. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs>. A Cossack brigade crossed the Korean border and encountered the Korean army. 30 Cossacks were killed and the rest escaped with their life. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs>. The minister of war <rs type="person"><ref source="person068">Kuropatkin</ref></rs> still hasn’t gone to the battlezone. He is truthfully preparing greatly for war, but he is still waiting for more 
               military to arrive. Until now, the military transport has been slow and chaotic. The trains are not heated and hundreds of soldiers froze to death on the way. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>. Chinese citizens are agitated; they want <rs type="place"><ref source="place021">China</ref></rs> to fall in with <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and declare 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> war. The Chinese government is waiting until it is clear whether <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> will also emerge as a victor on land. Then it will surely start a war. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs>. Three Japanese men, dressed as nuns, have been captured on the Siberian railroad to destroy a massive bridge. - The Russian government gave orders to keep a strict watch on the bridges.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>. Serbian and Montenegrin veterans enlisted in the Russian military as volunteers. They shouldn’t be more than 1,000 men and not older than 42 years.
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place007">Vienna</ref></rs>. The Czech members of the Austrian parliament sent a message to the tsar in which they
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[5]</p><pb/>
            <p>
               wish him to prevail over <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> (It will surely help him a lot!).
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>. News from <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs> reports that the Russian military withdraws everything continuously.  It will probably vacate a big part of 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs> and expect the Japanese military in the city <rs type="place"><ref source="place175">Harbin</ref></rs> where the first great battle on land will take place. 
            </p>
            <p>
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place082">Vladivostok</ref></rs>. The Japanese managed to dispose of the military on the landward side of <rs type="place"><ref source="place082">Vladivostok</ref></rs>. It will soon besiege the fortress from all sides. 
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="10">
            <head style="text-align:center">Cancer</head>   
            <p>
               Cancer is one of the most dangerous and most serious illnesses. Healing cancer is impossible. For now the only way to save a person from death is surgery, but surgery only helps in the first stage of cancer when it hasn’t spread through the body. Or 
               if the cancer is located in a limb which can be cut off completely. Unfortunately, cancer is almost never found in the early stages; when it is found it has usually progressed far. And the risk is really high.
            </p>
            <p>
               Cancer leads to death either by destroying an important part of the body or by debilitating the body or by releasing vigorous poison into the flesh. The tumour is easy to cut out with a knife, but it will soon spread out in new tumours. 
               Professor <rs type="person"><ref source="person102">Billroth</ref></rs> is the first who managed to cut out cancer of the innermost parts of the body. But the cancer is hardly ever cut out completely, the majority remains in the body. 
               Either it is not found or the tumour takes over too much space in the body and the surgeon has to put their knife down. Cancer grows well in the human body and spreads more and more until it is lethal.
            </p>
            <p>
               Cancer can grow in any part of the human body. Men and women get cancer, but women suffer in greater percentages. However, mainly older people develop cancer.
            </p>
            <p>
               Where the illness comes from is not known yet. Looking at the tumour through a microscope, one can see that it is made up of small cells which grow in the human flesh. The cells grow and multiply intensely, they spread with the ordinary 
               cells of which the human flesh consists of and through which blood and other fluids are transported through the body. The cancer grows and grows until only cancer remains in the body. Then it starts to swell and decay.
            </p>
            <p>
               Why and how it is growing those cells in the body - that question still remains unanswered. Lately, a theory goes around that cancer stems from particularly small<cb/> beings (microbes) which can neither be spotted with the blind eye nor with 
               current enlargers. They transmitted the cancer onto other creatures to prove that cancer, like any contagious disease, only stems from microbes. This hypothesis proves that the microbes causing tumors are particular ones and if those microbes 
               are cultivated the illness can be transferred to others. This hypothesis has been put out into the world several times already, but stricter research proved that it is too early to support this claim. In any case, this theory that special microbes 
               cause cancer is becoming more certain. At the last medical congress in <rs type="place"><ref source="place219">Wiesbaden</ref></rs>, professor <rs type="person"><ref source="person103">Leyden</ref></rs> said to have found the cancer microbe. 
               Prof. <rs type="person"><ref source="person103">Leyden</ref></rs> reckoned that cancer growth can only be explained by living organisms. The spread of cancer, he said, is the same as every other disease of which we know. It has to stem from microbes. 
               Cancer causes the same change in the blood and the same bodily depletion. Prof. <rs type="person"><ref source="person103">Leyden</ref></rs> also provides proof how the cancer was spread from one living creature to another. It is very much possible 
               that humans can also get infected but that is yet to be proven. He merely said that he had met with a young doctor who once drank the juice of a tumour. After two years the doctor got sick - stomach cancer. Prof. <rs type="person"><ref source="person103">Leyden</ref></rs> 
               found special microbes in cancer patients which he thinks to be the cause of cancer. They are found en masse under the skin and multiply heavily and grow into a big blister. This blister bursts and new blisters with new microbes form. 
            </p>
            <p>
               If <rs type="person"><ref source="person103">Leyden</ref></rs>’s theory can be proven, it will have a great impact. Not only is the cause known, but the possibility of healing grows. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Researching cancer is becoming more and more important, because more and more get sick from cancer. In 1892, two out of every 100 dying in <rs type="place"><rs type="place010">Germany</rs></rs> died of cancer. In 1898, it already increased to three. 
               Calculated differently, out of 100,000 living people 60 died of cancer in 1892. In 1898 this number rose to 71. In a period of seven years cancer grew to 18 %. 
            </p>
            <p>
               The same proliferation of cancer diseases were also found in other countries. In <rs type="place"><ref source="place011">England</ref></rs>, out of every million living people, 384 people died of cancer from 1861 to 1870. In the next ten years 468, in 
               the next 589 and in the last decade 829. In <rs type="place"><ref source="place220">Holland</ref></rs>, 49 people out of every 100,000 died of cancer in 1874, in 1897 114 died, and in 1898 the number grew to 132. In <rs type="place"><ref source="place096">New York</ref></rs> 
               2,473 people died of cancer in 1888 and 4117 in 1893.
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[6]</p><pb/>
            <p>These numbers show that the disease is multiplying more and more and starting to affect younger people more as well.</p>
            <p>Because of the danger and increasing number of cancer patients, scholars are interested more in cancer. Several capable doctors and professors are researching the disease. Even specialised science committees have been founded to collect material to research the disease. 
               It is important to know whether the sickness can be spread from human to human, if it can be inherited from parents to children and so on. The spread of the disease has become important for everyone and more and more private people are donating huge sums to scientific studies of cancer.</p>
            <p>If more knowledge about the disease is collected, where it comes from and how it grows, there could also be a way to fight against it.</p>
         </div>
         <div n="11">
            <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Feutellion<lb/> 
               <rs type="person"><ref source="person046">Rabbi Meir</ref></rs> of <rs type="place"><ref source="place099">Rothenburg</ref></rs><lb/>(A historical retelling)<lb/>(Continuation)</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               This time the <ref source="person044">count</ref> again did not listen although the rabbi told him about the precarious situation of the Jews. The count said again: 
            </p>
            <p>
               “I know that you are respected among Jews everywhere and that your name is shared amongst the Jewry far away. From every country, Jews are sending you their questions and your words are highly esteemed. Now is the right time to prove your loyalty to your fatherland and your love for your protector, 
               your majesty, the emperor. Although the Jews living under my authority are not as wealthy they should still support the government during the war. Only because you are honoured everywhere you must strive for all of your brothers in <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs>, 
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place067">Poland</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place027">Moravia</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Hungary</ref></rs>, and so on, to be submissive to you as well and absolutely should collect money as well. And I am certain everyone 
               will follow you, because it is known everywhere that your words are truly holy and more valuable than gold and silver.
            </p>
            <p>
               “Your good, honoured count, make me proud - answered the rabbi - you make me greater than all other rabbis; but truthfully, I am not worth the honour you allocate to me. From the time the First Temple was destroyed, we lost our sovereignty and our orders. We cannot command anyone to fulfill 
               his religious duties. Only those who are still loyal to their faith and religion are coming to us out of free will. On the contrary, but no single rabbi, no matter how honoured he may be, between adhering to the rules of the holy Torah and those who ask me for advice, I can only voice my opinion, 
               but I cannot force anyone to follow me. Furthermore, with such a hard thing that you, honoured count ask of me, I can certainly say that no one will listen to me.”
            </p><cb/>
            <p>
               After the rabbi explained, the count rushed over to him and declared with a thundering voice: “Listen up rabbi, I do not need your nonsensical speeches. I believe the cunning, reasonable person who told me you can predicate anything if you want to. And only because of that I called for you, 
               to tell you what your Majesty the emperor wants.
            </p>
            <p>
               “You should know that I chose you, only you, to execute all of this. The emperor’s will is not to be changed. In two months time you have to collect 20,000 ducats and in three months you have to deliver this sum to the imperial treasury. You should know that you alone with your head on the 
               line are responsible for this. You alone have to calculate how much everyone can give based on their wealth. Recompensation is in the emperor’s hands. If you can fulfill the wishes of the emperor, the one guarding all your brothers in all the emperor’s lands, he will have mercy on your 
               brothers who are asking for it from the emperor”.
            </p>
            <p>
               The rabbi left the count’s quarters with a broken heart and went back home. He has to tell his students who have looked up to him for a long time already, what the count said to him. After he told his students everything the count told him, they all got very somber because they all knew the 
               count and that he would not lower the sum! It is not possible and if only a little bit of money is missing, the count is willing to destroy all Jews. So, they all left from the rabbi with great aggravation and sorrow. 
            </p>
            <p>
               However, the rabbi, although his thoughts were very saddened, thought about the count’s speech closely. Only he, the rabbi will be made responsible for everything and that is why his faith in the Lord was not lost. He can do whatever he wants but no one under God’s will can prevail. The other 
               day he started writing letters to all his acquaintances who have written to him before and informed them of the danger looming over the Jewish people who are living under the rule of <rs type="person"><ref source="person044">Württemberg</ref></rs>. If they cannot collect 20,000 ducats in the 
               next month and again the same amount in three months, all Jews will be lost. However, he did mention that his head alone is on the line for it, because the rabbi thought if he conveyed this, everyone would give more than they can. But if all Jews are in danger they will send the money they are able to and not more. 
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center">
               (To be continued)
            </p>
         </div>
         <div n="12">
            <head style="text-align:center">Post box.
               <lb/><hi rend="italic">To several subscribers</hi></head>
            <p>
               The advertised booklet about <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Asian Russia</ref></rs> as well as the prayer book, the bonus for our half year subscribers, will be sent out next week.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         <div n="13">
             <div type="ad">
                  <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Fine tea</hi></head>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>If you want to drink pure, unadulterated tea, write to the address below,
                     <lb/>1 kg fine, pure tea only 6 crowns.
                     <lb/>There is also tea costing 3 to 10 crowns per kg.
                     <lb/>Sample for free and prepaid.
                     <lb/><rs type="person">L. Aperman</rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place132">Brody</ref></rs> <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs>.
                     <lb/>Thee &amp; Caffe Lager.
                  </p>
                  <p style="text-align:center">[7]</p><pb/>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="14">
               <head style="text-align:center"><hi rend="bold">Last News.</hi></head>
               <div><head style="text-align:center">A great win for <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Japan</ref></rs>.</head>
                  <p><rs type="place"><ref source="place031">Berlin</ref></rs>. The local paper “<ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q821625">Berliner Lokal-Anzeiger</ref>" received a telegram in the last hour. In <rs type="place"><ref source="place022">Korea</ref></rs>, 
                     80 kilometres away from the city <rs type="place"><ref source="place221">Pyongyang</ref></rs> where the Japanese main battalions were stationed, the Russians and Japanese erupted into a great battle. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Japan</ref></rs> won gloriously.</p></div>
               <div><head style="text-align:center"><rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Russia</ref></rs> wants to withdraw.</head>
                  <p><rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>. The Russian ambassador in <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>, Count <rs type="person"><ref source="person104">Benckendorff</ref></rs> went to <rs type="place"><ref source="place018">St Petersburg</ref></rs> 
                     at the start of the war already where he stayed for a few days before he went back to <rs type="place"><ref source="place156">London</ref></rs>. Since his return, he went to King <rs type="person"><ref source="person105">Edward</ref></rs> and, as it is rumoured in political circles, 
                     wants him to take care of the peace mediation between <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>. <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> wants to retreat from <rs type="place"><ref source="place028">Manchuria</ref></rs> 
                     and hand <rs type="place"><ref source="place083">Port Arthur</ref></rs> over to <rs type="place"><ref source="place019">Japan</ref></rs>. That is why it should conclude peace.</p></div>
               <div><head style="text-align:center">Victory of the government in <rs type="place"><ref source="place009">Hungary</ref></rs>.</head>
               <p><rs type="place"><ref source="place030">Budapest</ref></rs>. The Hungarian government achieved a massive goal in the parliament. As the opposition noticed that the government was serious with changing its rules of order and was also ready to enforce this change with violence in order to 
                  render the obstruction impossible, the opposition conceded. The minister president <rs type="person"><ref source="person005">Tisza</ref></rs> retracted his motion to change the rules, but the opposition obliged to sign off the recruitment act and other important laws. (Read the article 
                  “<rs type="place"><ref source="place009">Hungary</ref></rs>’s situation” in the Tuesday feature.)</p></div>
         </div>
         <div>
            <p>The editor does not take responsibility for the advertisements in this paper.</p>
            <div style="text-align:center">
               <p>Bank and exchange business
                  <lb/>ROHAYTN &amp; ULAM
                  <lb/><foreign xml:lang="de"><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lemberg</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place186">Syxtuskagasse</ref></rs> 8.</foreign>
                  <lb/>Buying and selling all kinds of
                  <lb/>Effects, lotteries, and coins.
                  <lb/>Lottery available in cheap installments.
                  <lb/>At request, a lottery calendar for 1904
                  <lb/>can be given for free.
                  <lb/>Easy, low-interest loans available.</p>
            </div><cb/>
            <div><p>Important for farmers
               On occasion of the upcoming spring season, we suggest the following enterprise for buying bonemeal, clay slag, phosphates, and so on. Any and all grasses, clover seeds and agricultural machines by the most prestigious factories, domestic and abroad. 
               Illustrated price lists can be sent for free and without shipping costs on request. 
               The delivery will make customers satisfied and accomplished to the max.</p> 
               
               <div><p><rs type="person"><ref source="person106">NATHAN SPRECHER</ref></rs>
               Artificial fertilizer, seeds &amp; machinery
               <rs type="place"><ref source="place223">Podgórze</ref></rs> - <rs type="place"><ref source="place149">Kraków</ref></rs>
</p></div>               
               
               <div><p><ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q17590684">The Oesterreichische 
                  <lb/>Volkszeitung</ref>
                  <lb/>Which is published with 82,000 copies publishes important
                  <lb/>news 
                  <lb/>about the RUSSO-JAPANESE 
                  <lb/>WAR
                  <lb/>as well as MANY TIDINGS from all around the world, interesting and tasteful literature to 
                  <lb/>ENTERTAIN and EDUCATE
                  <lb/>two thrilling novels daily, one SUBSTANTIALLY tasteful family insert
                  <lb/>The SUBSCRIPTION COSTS amount to:
                  <lb/>For one daily, postpaid shipment in <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place142">Bosnia</ref></rs>; 2.70 K. monthly, 7.90 K quarterly. For twice weekly shipments of the 
                  <lb/>SATURDAY- and THURSDAY-EDITIONS
                  <lb/>(with novel- and family-insert [in book form], extensive newsreel etc.); 2.64 K. quarterly, 5.20 K. for six months. For weekly shipments of the rich SATURDAY-EDITION (with novel- and family-insert [in book form], extensive newsreel etc.); 1.70 K quarterly, 3.30 K every six months.
                  <lb/>Daily subscriptions can start at any point, weekly subscriptions can only be started at the beginning of the month.
                  <lb/>FREE TRIALS
                  <lb/>The editorial office of the “Oesterreichische 
                  <lb/>Volkszeitung”, <rs type="place"><ref source="place007">Vienna</ref>, 1010</rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place222">Schulerstraße</ref> 16</rs>.
                  <lb/>All new subscribers receive the current, highly interesting novels and novellas for free.</p></div> 
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="footer" style="one columns" n="1">
            <p>
               <foreign xml:lang="de">
                  <lb/>Herausgeber und verantwortlicher Redact. <rs type="person"><ref source="person031">OSIAS H. WILF</ref></rs>
                  recte Weinstock <lb/>Druck von <rs type="person"><ref source="person032">E. Salat</ref></rs> Witwe des <rs
                     type="person"><ref source="person033">U.W. Salat</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place002"
                        >Lemberg</ref></rs>
                  <rs type="place"><ref source="place065">Kasimirgasse 35</ref></rs>
               </foreign>
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[8]</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
