<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" source="1904-02-26.xml">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="s">The Genuine Jew - 1904-02-26</title>
            <title level="a">1904-02-26</title>
            <author>Multiple Authors</author>
            <editor>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </editor>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>TGJ</edition>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Translation</resp>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </respStmt>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <name>Luger, Robin</name>
            </publisher>
            <pubPlace>Vienna</pubPlace>
            <date when="2025">2025</date>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">
                  <p>You are free to: Share — copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format; adapt — remix, transform, and build upon the material
                     for any purpose, even commercially.</p>
                  <p>The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms. Under the following terms:</p>
                  <p>Attribution — You must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use. No additional restrictions — You may not apply legal terms or technological measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license permits.</p>
                  <p>Notices:</p>
                  <p>You do not have to comply with the license for elements of the material in the public domain or where your use is permitted by an applicable exception or limitation. No warranties are given. The license may not give you all of the permissions necessary for your intended use. For example, other rights such as publicity, privacy, or moral rights may limit how you use the material.</p>
               </licence>
               <p>Copyright 2021 Österreichische Nationalbibliothek</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>A</country>
                  <settlement>Vienna</settlement>
                  <repository>Austrian National Library</repository>
                  <collection></collection>
                  <idno>429702-D NEU PER</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when-iso="1904-02-19">1904-02-26</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Sonngasse 27, Lemberg</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
   <facsimile source="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/anno?aid=emj&amp;datum=19040226">
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="1">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|1|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="2">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|2|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="3">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|3|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="4">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|4|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="5">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|5|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="6">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|6|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4257" lry="6222" n="7">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|7|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
      <surface ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4305" lry="6222" n="8">
         <graphic url="https://anno.onb.ac.at/cgi-content/annoshow?call=emj|19040226|8|100.0|0"></graphic>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div type="heading" n="1" style="one column">
            
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">1.Jahrgang 	Nr. 4 </foreign>	1st year</p>
         </div>
         <div type="title" n="1">
            <head>
               <hi rend="bold">The Geniune Jew</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Organ for yiddish matters</p>
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">DER WAHRE JUDE</foreign></p>
            <p><foreign xml:lang="de">Organ für die Gesammtinteressen des Judenthums</foreign></p>
         </div>
         <div type="editorial" n="1" style="two columns">
            <cb n="1"/>
            <table rows="4" cols="2">
               <head>The Geniune Jew costs</head>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">In <rs type="place"><ref source="place001">Austria-Hungary</ref></rs></cell>
                  <cell role="data">Abroad</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 8 Kronen</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 12 Francs</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 4 "</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 6 "</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 2.50 "</cell>
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 3.50 "</cell>
               </row>
            </table>
            <p><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>,<date when-iso="1904-02-19"> Friday 26th 1904</date></p>
            <cb n="2"/>
            <p>
               <lb/>Adverts are cheaply calculated
               <lb/>All letters and money send to:
               <lb/><foreign xml:lang="de">Redaction "Der wahre Jude",<rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>, <rs type="place"><ref source="place003">Sonnengasse 27</ref></rs></foreign>
               <lb/>The Genuine Jew is published every Friday.
               <lb/><foreign xml:lang="de"><rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lemberg</ref></rs>, <date when-iso="1904-02-26">den 26. Februar 1904</date></foreign>.</p>
         </div>
         <lb/>
         <div type="article" style="two columns" n="1">
           <head><hi rend="bold">The Genuine Jew
            <lb/>Twice a week</hi></head>
            <p>We are delighted to announce to our readers and our friends that our hope with “The Genuine Jew”, to create a readership and be of use for our brothers, especially our pious brothers, was fulfilled. Already, after 
               three issues of “The Genuine Jew”, our paper has gained popularity among the people. Starting on Thursday, people start to ask every tobacconist's, every bookstore and even the editor’s office, whether the new edition 
               has already arrived. Our readers can barely wait until the print has finished. Everything is bought, for example, we have not a single copy left of No. 3, although we printed a huge batch.</p>
            <p>Not only the news about the war made people interested in this paper. From all over, people tell us that the audience, especially our Orthodox brothers who are the reason we established the paper, are very satisfied. 
               The articles mainly focusing on Jewish topics proved popular among the general public. For the first time, there is a Jewish newspaper in <rs type="place"><ref source="place006">Galicia</ref></rs> which every pious Jew 
               can read, including his wife and children without having to fear to stray from the path of righteousness.</p>
            <p>The audience is content with us and we are content with the audience. This mutual satisfaction allows us to improve and prosper our paper.</p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[1]</p>
            <p>Voices from different quarters ask for the paper to be released <hi rend="italic">daily</hi>, but we want to follow what our scholars of blessed memories have said: “If you grasp too much, you will grasp nothing” 
               and not to put too much work on our backs. Therefore, we decided to first  carry out a small test, namely: from next week on </p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">The Genuine Jew
               <lb/>comes out twice a week
               <lb/>Tuesday and Friday
            </p>
            <p>Friday will stay like it is now with the same content. On Tuesday, we will preliminarily write about news from the war front, politics and similar topics our readers care about and cannot wait for until Friday.</p>
            <p>We live in serious times. More wars will follow the war between <rs type="place"><ref source="place014">Russia</ref></rs> and <rs type="place"><ref source="place19">Japan</ref></rs>. The whole world, generally the Jew, 
               is curious to know what happens around the globe. And if there is no Jewish press he has to purchase newspapers in other languages which are more expensive and he might not understand them well. 
               Therefore, if “The Genuine Jew” comes out twice a week, he will be able to  satisfy his needs concerning a <hi rend="italic">Jewish</hi> paper.</p>
            <p style="text-align:center">The price of our paper “The Genuine Jew”
               <lb/>twice a week will be
            </p>
            <table rows="3" cols="1" style="text-align:center">
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a whole year - 12 Francs</cell>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <cell role="data">For a half year - 6 "</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell role="data">For a quarter year - 3.50 "</cell>
               </row>
            </table>
            <p style="text-align:center">Single Issues: Friday 10 heller, Tuesday 6 heller.</p>
            <p style="text-align:right">The editorial office.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" style="one column" n="2">
            <head rend="bold" style="text-align:center">The cultus elections in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs></head>
            <p>In the first articles of three issues of “The Genuine Jew” various writers rightfully pointed at several important questions regarding Jewish existence which are not handled as they should be. The writers allude 
               to our ample negligence of Jewry as in every nook we are pointing to in order to criticize. The upbringing of our children, our religious education, our rabbis; briefly speaking: at home, in school and even in the 
               rabbis’ dwellings. Everywhere is room for improvements and every writer asks: Who is at fault?</p>
            <p>Who is at fault? Answering this question is not easy because we are all guilty: our sons and our elders, young and old, we all are guilty that <cb/>the Jewry is getting weaker and weaker. Our parents do not parent 
               our children well. Our religion teachers teach badly. Even our rabbis do not have any power, any influence. It has to become better here. Because of the rabbinical question, are our rabbis without power or influence, 
               they are dependent on our cultus board and therefore do not dare to open their mouth and demand for things to improve.</p>
            <p>And here we come to our main conclusion to our question: Who is at fault? Guilty is our cultus board, the leaders of our communities.  They are not taking a stance and act correctly according to their duty.</p>
            <p>The communities act as  autonomous bodies. This means they have the right to manage all affairs regarding their community on their own</p>
            <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">[2]</p><pb/>
            <p>without anyone intervening. In any other nation an autonomous entity like this would act in favour of its own people. It would use its force and influence to improve the prevailing conditions. Here however, it is 
               different. Our ministry of cultural affairs mainly consists of mere <hi rend="italic">chanceries</hi>. Books are taken care of, they stipulate how things should be running. There is an accountant, a cashier, and a 
               controller. The council gets together every once in a while to talk about current matters, a bit about politics, about the Landtag elections and things like that. But they do not talk about Jewish matters, about 
               the significant interests of the Jewish people - those are not discussed as if the council is not responsible for them. </p>
            <p>
               The cause of this is very simple. In most Galician cities, the majority of Jews living there are pious ones. However, the electives in the ministry are mainly “progressive” lawyers who are not particularly interested 
               in Jewish matters. Whenever this council gets together in a meeting, they are clueless what to do in favour of religion and faith. First of all, they do not know a lot about it and do not know how to enact a remedy. 
               Secondly, they are more progressive and cannot act against their own opinion of Jewry. It is already sufficient if they do not do anything to harm Jewry as they are afraid of the pious populace. More than that, 
               everything is neglected. The council does not care about the religious education, not about the rabbinical question, not about the תּלמוד־תּורה (Talmetoyre - a tuition-free elementary school maintained by the community 
               for poor children), they do not care about Jewish upbringing. Therefore, everything here is foul and bad. 
            </p>
            <p>
               Why do we talk about this whole thing here? Shortly, there will be an election for the new board of culture in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs>, the capital of the country. The smaller towns 
               look up to the big city and adapt themselves towards it. The state of the big city has an influence on the small towns. If everything is working properly in the city, everything will be alright in the smaller cities. 
               Moreover, elections in a big community, a community of major cultural and religious importance - like the one in <rs type="place"><ref source="place002">Lviv</ref></rs> - are significant for the whole country and 
               have a bigger impact than just locally. The outcome of the elections can influence the entire country -  for the better or for the worse. And we pious Jews need to see that it will be better.</p>
            <p>We do not want to look into the programs and moreover single individuals and parties yet. There still will be enough time for that. Today we want to concern ourselves with the question in order to remind our pious 
               brothers of the upcoming elections which are very important for the Jewry and<pb/> to call on them to pay their overdue taxes in order to not lose their right to vote. They should make an effort to attain as many votes 
               as they can. For these elections, every vote has an immense value. This time they need to use their voice for the benefit of the true Jewry. If we manage to improve the situation in the ministry of culture and education, 
               everything will gradually improve.</p>
               <p style="text-align:right">- The observer.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article" style="two columns" n="3">
            <head rend="bold" style="text-align:center">Our daughter’s education.
               <lb/>II.
            </head>
            <p>
               I must admit that the impression my first article on pious family has made, was bigger than I anticipated. This shows that I portrayed the situation correctly. The critique, what I have criticised was right therefore. 
               However, it is not as easy to point a way to improve the conditions. The main action is for the parents to care more about their daughter’s education as much as they should stick to the rule: “One who is created needs 
               to marry, but does not need to live”. This means: do only men need to live piously? Do only our sons need to be educated well, Jewish, and piously, but not our daughters? Women today play a big role in our family life. 
               Not only is the Jewry at home, the <ref source="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q191498">kashrut</ref>, the desecration of Sabbath, amongst other things, dependent on them, because the men are busy making a living to 
               take care of the household. They are not responsible for the children’s and particularly the daughter’s upbringing, but if their daughters are not educated Jewish, one can imagine them wanting to raise their daughters 
               again. Still, the pious Jewry should strive to educate their daughters as well as their sons. They have to see that their daughter’s do not leave school which is a legal requirement which no one can withdraw from. 
               They have to see that their daughter’s do not spend their days reading corrupt novels which turn them bad. They have to see that their daughter’s educate themselves economically, they should know cooking, baking, 
               sewing, stitching and so on. It is necessary for every Jewish housewife to concern themselves with this matter if they do not want to deal with  some blockhead, if they do not want to be associated with bad company, 
               and to not be unhappy with themselves and make their parents miserable. If they strive for education and knowledge, they can gather enough Jewish knowledge. They can learn to understand our prayers and our poems, 
               learn a bit of Jewish history, they need to know how much the Jewish people have suffered for their religion and their faith, how many martyrs have devoted themselves, were burnt and drowned for our holy religion. 
               They therefore should be planted deep in the young hearts, love, and respect for their people, their religion, to their customs, and their performances. At that time, the honest, pious Jew has not been the target 
               of mockery, at that time they were not looked at like people from past generations, at that time they felt what every pious Jew felt, back then they would know that they are
            </p>
            <p style="text-align:center">[3]</p><pb/>
            <p>
               Jewish daughters, that they have Jewish duties. At that time, the old, magnificent Jewish family life could develop and it will be as it was written in the scripture: May peace dwell in your community and tranquillity 
               in your homes!
            </p>
         </div>
            
         <div type="ads" n="1" style="one column">
            <head>The editor does not take responsibility for the advertisements in this paper.</head>
            <div type="ad" n="1" style="two columns">
               <head><hi rend="bold">Fine tea</hi></head>
               <p>
                  <lb/>If you want to drink pure, unadulterated tea, write to the address below,
                  <lb/>1 kg fine, pure tea only 6 crowns.
                  <lb/>There is also tea costing 3 to 10 crowns per kg.
                  <lb/>Sample for free and prepaid.
                  <lb/><rs type="person">L. Aperman</rs>, <rs type="place">Brody</rs> <rs type="place">Galicia</rs>.
                  <lb/>Thee &amp; Caffe Lager.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="ad" n="2" style="two columns">
               <head>The proof of the pudding</head>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Is in the eating.
                  <lb/>If you want a natural, working remedy for coughing, sore throats, congestion, against  digestive problems, lack of appetite or similar problems, you should try the remedy from the first 
                  Austrian malt extract brewery of the brothers Bittman in <rs type="place">Razová</rs> in <rs type="place">Schlesien</rs>:
                  <lb/>Healthy Malt-Extract
                  <lb/>Which healing-powers have been proven and recommended by numerous thank yous and appreciation letters. Just one teaspoon concentrated malt-extract dissolved in a cup of hot milk sweetened 
                  with some pieces of malt or sugar is not only an exquisite expectorant remedy for a cold or the flu, but also works as a 
                  <lb/>powerful malt breakfast
                  <lb/>for children, the preferred nutrition for bone formation and hematosis compared to the other malt coffee variety of today. - 
                  <lb/>Price per jar 80 guilders. Malt pieces per package 20 guilders.
                  <lb/>Half a box: 6 jars 92-94 crowns. A whole box: 12 jars 70-78 crowns. Payment on delivery.
               </p>               
            </div>
            <div type="ad" n="3" style="two columns">
               <head><hi rend="bold">The sugar refinery of <rs type="place">Przeworsk</rs></hi></head>
               <p>
                  Has immensely scaled up its sugar production for 1904 and recommends every variety to extremely low prices.
                  <lb/>You can get various useful instructions for register handlers, head of cultural affairs, private individuals, etc. at different prices.
                  <lb/>S. Weinstock, in <rs type="place">Lviv</rs>,<rs type="place"> Rzeznicka 5 [Nalyvaika St]</rs>
               </p>
            </div>
            <cb/>
            <div>
               <head><hi rend="bold">Coffee</hi></head>
               <p>The best varieties are sent in 5 kilogram packages prepaid against sending details, the rest payment on delivery, sending to all towns of <rs type="place">Austria-Hungary</rs>.
               <lb/>Everything duty-free
               <lb/>5 kg  Santos fine 6 guildes - 5 kg Santos prima 6.20 guildes. - 5kg Kuba fine 7.50 guildes - 5kg Kuba prima 7.90 guildes - 5 kg Gold-Menados 7.60 guildes - 5 kg Gold-Java 7.60 guildes - 5 kg Ceylon super fine 9 guildes - 5 kg San Salvador 7 guildes - 5 kg Puerto Rica very strong 7.50 guildes - 5 kg Mokka super fine 9.20 guildes</p>
               
               <p><rs type="person">IGNATZ RATH</rs>, <rs type="place">TRIEST</rs> I.
               <lb/>Südfrüchten Versandt en gros &amp; en detail.
              </p>
            </div>
            <div type="ad" n="4" style="two columns">
               <head>Stable employment</head>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Fixed salary and provision after a trial period for every person who dedicates themselves to an agency in the countryside. Part-time employment possible. Expertise is not needed, reliability needed.
                  <lb/>Application to:
                  <lb/><rs type="person">A. Hübscher</rs>, <rs type="place">Prague</rs>.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="ad" n="5" style="two columns">
               <head>
                  <lb/><hi rend="bold">Coffee!</hi>
                  <lb/><hi rend="italic>">All natural!</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  Also less than 5 kg, payment on delivery, prepaid, postage.
               </p>
               <table rows="3" cols="2">
                  <row role="data">
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place">Santos</rs> Coffee á 1,20 guilders</cell>
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place">Puerto Rico</rs> Pearl á 1,23 guilders</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row role="data">
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place">Cuba</rs>     "    "  1,46 "</cell>
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place">Ceylon</rs>     "     "  1,68 "  </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row role="data">
                     <cell role="data"><rs type="place">Ceylon</rs>  "   "    1,62  "</cell>
                     <cell role="data">Gold <rs type="place">Java</rs>   "   "   1,45 "</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
               <lb/>
               <p>
                  Free samle and payment on delivery
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs type="person">Berger Ernö</rs>, <rs type="place">Fuime</rs>.
               </p>
         </div>
            <div type="ad" n="6" style="two columns">
            <head>
               <rs type="person">Joel Weinreb</rs> <rs type="place">Lviv</rs>
               <lb/><rs type="place">Krakivska St 32
               <lb/>Corner Yana Zhyzhky 2</rs>
            </head>
            <p>
               Recommends the biggest special for fabric shopping, a magazine of the latest silk and wool. Fur and velvet for clothes, French linen, English carpets, slates, canvases, weaving and garnishes.
               <lb/>A particularly big selection of English carpets, airy portiers, lace curtains, sheep wool and silk, duvets and comforters, furniture fabrics etc.
               <lb/>The latest novelties are always on shelf for cheap prices.
            </p>  
         </div>
      </div>
      <div type="footer" style="one columns" n="1">
         <p>
            <foreign xml:lang="de">
               <lb/>Herausgeber und verantwortlicher Redact. <rs type="person">OSIAS H. WILF</rs> recte Weinstock
               <lb/>Druck von <rs type="person">E. Salat</rs> Witwe des <rs type="person">U.W. Salat</rs>, <rs type="place">Lemberg</rs> <rs type="place">Kasimirgasse 35</rs>
            </foreign>
         </p>   
         <p style="text-align:center" rend="bold">[8]</p>
        </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>








